sctax.org 2010-11-20

# Privacy Statement

### South Carolina Department Of Revenue  
Privacy Statement

**Overview** In general, our online policies governing the collection and dissemination of personally identifiable information follow the same rules that would apply to an in-person visit to our office, and are governed by the same state and federal laws that cover such visits. **Purpose**

The purpose of the statement is to inform users of this site with regard to the collection and use of personally identifiable information.  Nothing herein should be construed to, nor does it, create any new or different rights than those available under existing State and federal laws.

 **Definition of Personally Identifiable Information**

For the purposes of this statement, "personally identifiable information" means any information relating to an identified or identifiable individual who is the subject of the information.  This includes information such as names, addresses, social security numbers and credit card numbers.

 **Personally Identifiable Information Not Routinely Collected**

Users are not required to provide personal information simply to visit our Web sites or to download information.  We may request personally identifiable information in order to provide requested specialized services, but such information is handled as it would be on an in-person visit to a government office.

 **Personally Identifiable Information that May Be Subject to Public Disclosure**

   In the state of South Carolina, laws exist to ensure that government is open and that the public has a right to access appropriate records and information possessed by a government agency.  At the same time, there are exceptions to the public's right to access certain records in order to preserve the privacy of individuals.  Such exemptions are authorized by both State and federal laws.  Information collected by us, like information collected during an in-person visit our office, may be subject to inspection and copying by the public, unless such an exemption in law exists.  In the event that there is a conflict between this Privacy Statement and a State or federal law governing the disclosure of public records, the applicable State or federal law shall control.

The Family Privacy Protection Act of 2002 prohibits persons or private entities from using any personal information obtained from the Department's web site for commercial solicitation purposes. A person knowingly violating this prohibition is guilty of a misdemeanor and subject to the penalties specified in 30-2-50 (D).

 **Use, Collection and Retention of Personally Identifiable Information**

The IP (Internet Protocol) addresses of computers used to visit our Web sites are noted as part of the statistical analysis used to better design government services and improve access to them.  However, we do not attempt to gain personally identifiable information on individual users or to associate individual users with IP addresses.

We collect, retain, and use personal information about constituents only when: 1)  they choose to subscribe to a service, and 2) where it is lawful and is essential to administer and to provide products, services and other opportunities requested by a constituent.

 **Use of Cookies**

Our Web applications may create "cookies" to hold user information.  These "cookies" are then sent to, and stored on, the user's computer.  This information is handled in the same way as other personally identifiable information obtained by us.  No user information will be gathered through the use of "cookies" except that which is required to run the specific application(s) being accessed by the user.

 **Use of Constituent E-mail Addresses**

E-mail addresses obtained as a result of requests to our Web sites will not be sold or given to any organization for marketing purposes. The information collected is subject to the access and confidentiality provisions of the State's Freedom of Information Act and other applicable sections of the South Carolina Code of Laws and/or federal law. E-mail or other information requests sent to our Web sites may be maintained in order to: respond to the request, forward that request to the appropriate department or agency, communicate updates to the system that may be of interest to citizens, or provide our Web developers with valuable customer feedback to assist in improving the site.

 **Data Security and Quality**

We are committed to data security and the data quality of personally identifiable information that is either available from, or collected by, our Web sites, and have taken precautions to protect personally identifiable information from loss, misuse or alteration. Any third parties responsible for this information are committed to the same principles, and also are required by contract to follow the same policies and guidelines as the State of South Carolina in protecting this information. Unless otherwise prohibited by state or federal law, rule or regulation, individuals will be given the ability to access and correct personally identifiable information maintained by us that may be in error.

 **Non-Department of Revenue Web Sites**

Various Web sites will be linked through us. This includes Web sites of other governmental agencies, as well as Web sites of private entities. Many of these sites may not be subject to the South Carolina Code of Laws, or may operate under different privacy standards. Visitors to those Web sites are advised to check the privacy statements of those sites and be cautious about providing personally identifiable information without a clear understanding of how the information will be used.

 **Limiting Access to Personally Identifiable Information**

We have taken steps to limit access to personally identifiable information to support staff who require access in order to perform their assigned duties. We have notified and instructed our staff of their responsibilities concerning the protection of personally identifiable information.

 **Contact Us**

The person responsible for the administration of the Departments privacy policy is Michael D. Garon, CIO. (803)898-5586.

If you have questions about this privacy statement, the practices of this site, or your interaction with this web site, please contact:

South Carolina Department of Revenue

301 Gervais Street

Columbia, South Carolina  29201

* * *
